In May 1972, at an amusement park in Hokkaido.
1972年5月 在北海道的一個遊樂園裡
Rumors circulated about young women disappearing one after another.
流傳著年輕女性接連消失的傳聞
The rumor was that they were drugged
據說她們去上洗手間時
and abducted when they went to the restroom.
會被注射藥物，然後擄走
He's an abductor!
你是綁架犯！
Kidnapper!
你這綁匪！
However, no such incidents had actually occurred.
但實際上並沒有發生那樣的案件
Yet, in late May,
可是在5月下旬
the owner found himself surrounded by the public, on the verge of a riot.
老闆遭一般大眾包圍 差點就演變成暴動
Even though there were reports denying the rumors,
即使發布了否認謠言的報導
the situation didn't settle down.
事態並未因此平息
As with the amusement park incident,
遊樂園一事讓我們得知
rumors spread and don't die down even if they are known not to be true.
就算明白並非事實
Around the time the orifices appeared,
當洞出現的時候
there was an increase in people visiting hospitals due to asthma.
因氣喘到醫院治療的人增加了
Even after it became clear that the orifices weren't the cause,
即使後來已查明並非洞所造成的
many still kept blaming the orifices.
還是有許多人將錯歸咎於洞
People like to spread captivating lies even after the truth is revealed.
比起後來得知的真相 有趣的假情報更容易散播出去
Please do your part in spreading the real facts.
希望你們能確實傳播真相
Are there any warm drinks?
沒有熱飲對吧？
Wine can be warmed up, right?
可以把葡萄酒加熱吧？
Right.
對耶
I brought some camping gear, so I'll go get them.
我有帶露營用具來，就拿來用吧
Did we run out of wine?
葡萄酒已經沒了嗎？
No, we still have some.
還有剩喔
Um…
那個…
We all can see the orifices,
大家都看到了那些洞
but what if we're all just imagining them at the same time?
但其實是出於大家的想像 同時看到洞的話，你們會怎麼想？
Do you mean, what if they don't exist?
你是想說其實洞並不存在？
But we all believe they're there.
但我們現在都認為它存在
You mean, if everyone believes they're there, everyone can see them?
你的意思是人們同時認為它存在 所以才都看得到洞？
If so, where are the people who entered?
如果真的是這樣 那我們現在到底在哪？
I don't know about that.
那我就不知道了
Who wants some hot wine?
誰想喝熱葡萄酒？
I'd like some too.
我也想喝
Should we warm up the whole bottle or should we pour it in here and heat it up?
那是要整瓶加熱 還是倒進裡面煮沸？
Oh, I'll do it.
哦，我來弄就好
You're up next, Mr. Watanabe.
接下來換渡邊先生了
Oh, yeah.
哦，好
This story is a bit embarrassing for me to tell, especially in front of women.
我的故事說起來有點丟臉 特別在女性面前不太想提
I felt embarrassed too.
我的故事也很丟臉啊
Your story was fine.
不會啦
I have a sister who's a year older than me.
我有一個大我一歲的姊姊
Our parents divorced when we were young.
我還小的時候，父母就離婚了
We both went to live with our mother,
我們兩個人都決定跟著媽媽
and so we played together a lot.
所以我們很常玩在一起
When we were in junior high school, our father passed away
上國中的時候因為離婚的父親過世
and our mother had to pay off his debts.
我媽媽不得不償還他的債務
That's why my sister took on a part-time job when she started high school.
所以我姊姊上高中後便開始打工
And she got busy.
變得很忙
Anyway,
後來呢
we were both able to go to university.
我們兩個都還是有上大學
My sister started working after graduation but I didn't get a job.
姊姊畢業後便就業，但我沒有去工作
I wanted to take the judicial exam.
因為想挑戰司法考試
I've been studying meticulously and taking the exams until recently.
直到最近，我都還慎重地準備 實際去參加考試
How old are you now?
請問你現在幾歲？
I'm 54. Yeah…
54歲，對…
And…
然後呢
I even didn't get a part-time job.
我也沒去打工
I was relying on my mother to send me money and focused on studying.
我只顧著讀書 全靠媽媽給的錢過生活
Hello.
喂？
Have you taken on a part-time job?
你最近有開始打工嗎？
Um, no…
這個嘛，沒有耶
Well, you know, studying is harder than I thought.
讀書這件事比想像中還要難
Listen.
我說你啊
Shouldn’t you give up on the judicial exam?
還不放棄司法考試嗎？
How old are you?
你都已經幾歲了？
Well…
我想想…
How old am I again?
我到底幾歲啊？
Mom doesn't have the money to support you anymore.
媽媽已經沒有錢養你了
I want this to be the last time.
希望這是最後一次
It's going to be my 12th attempt anyway.
但接下來會是我第12次挑戰
Either way, I want this to be the last time she sends you money.
不管怎樣，以後不會再給你錢了
But…
可是啊
Even if I pass the exam, it'll still take time until I find a job.
就算我考上了 直到找到工作也需要一段時間
I will still be needing money during that time.
那段期間也會需要用錢
I wonder what I should do then.
到時候我該怎麼辦？
If you pass, I'll lend you a little money.
如果你考上了，我會借你一點錢
A loan…
用借的啊
What does Mom say about this?
媽媽她是怎麼說的？
What I just told you.
就是我剛才告訴你的那些話
For Watanabe, being cut off meant the end of his life.
對渡邊來說，沒了家人的資助 就代表人生的終結
Of course,
當然他也不是從未想過 母親老死之後的問題
But it was something he'd rather not think about, even more so than the exams.
但這對他來說 是比考試更加不願面對的事
What should I do then?
不然該怎麼做才好？
Should I just end my life here?
是要我就此結束人生嗎？
No, I just need 100,000 yen.
所以說我只要十萬圓就好
It's half of what Mom used to send me.
這只是媽媽給我的一半金額
You have a stable job, don't you?
姊姊，你的工作很穩定吧？
It's only until I find a part-time job.
至少讓我撐到找到打工為止啊
What should I become if I can't find a part-time job?
如果找不到兼職工作，我會怎麼樣？
So you do mean I should end my life.
所以你就是希望我的人生就此了結嘛
In the end, my sister didn't lend me money.
結果姊姊並沒有借我錢
But she introduced me to an acquaintance who owned a movie theater.
但有介紹我去她朋友的電影院工作
Enjoy.
請好好享受電影
They paid 500 yen for a drink that costs 100 yen at the convenience store.
他們用500圓來買 便利商店裡一杯100多圓的飲料
They bought two of those 500-yen drinks.
而且還買了兩杯
They were probably 20 years younger than me.
他們應該比我年輕20歲左右
With my hourly wage of 920 yen, I would have to work two hours.
對時薪920圓的我來說 要工作兩個小時才能在這裡買飲料
This guy will buy two colas and a premium popcorn.
這傢伙會買兩杯可樂跟升級版爆米花
Can I get two colas and a premium popcorn? The caramel one.
兩杯可樂跟升級版爆米花，焦糖口味
I can't afford this kind of lifestyle.
我過不了這種生活
If I had an income appropriate for my age, I could afford to eat and drink here too.
如果我有符合這年紀的收入 也能在這種地方吃吃喝喝
Excuse me, the movie's starting soon, so could you hurry?
不好意思，電影快開始了 能快點給我們嗎？
I'll be quick.
我盡快
I didn't want to breathe the same air as those who couldn't even plan
我不想和不先算好購物所需時間 就來看電影的傢伙
their shopping time before coming to the cinema.
呼吸同一種空氣
Oof.
嘿咻
Can I talk to you?
借一步說話
So, lately…
最近啊…
On the days you're working here,
只要是你上班的日子
the number of ice creams somehow doesn't add up.
冰品的庫存都會減少一些
-What? -No.
-什麼？ -少來了
Don't play dumb.
別裝傻
I mean,
雖然你每天都有排班 幫了我很大的忙
But I found it strange,
但我一直覺得不對勁
so I checked the surveillance cameras from the past days.
所以調閱了之前的監視器紀錄
Do you have anything to say?
你要解釋一下嗎？
Um, I'm not sure what to say.
那個，我不知道該說什麼
If you don't know what to say, it's okay.
不知道的話那就算了
Just wait here.
在這等一下
What are you going to do?
你打算怎麼做？
About what?
你指的是什麼？
If I die and I'm not around anymore, what will you do?
如果我死掉不在了，你該怎麼辦？
No one will help you.
沒有人會幫你
I need you to die before that.
在我死掉之前
Before I die.
你不先死就麻煩了
Watanabe's next part-time job was at a wedding hall.
渡邊接下來在婚宴會場打工
However, this didn't last long either.
但這個工作也沒有持續很久
Watanabe delved into quicker ways to turn his life around.
渡邊開始埋頭尋找 能迅速翻轉人生的方法
The most talked-about place now is Dubai.
近期倍受矚目的地方就是杜拜
With the right methods and strategies, even monkeys can become successful.
只要用對方法並掌握取勝訣竅 就連猴子都能大獲成功
I'm not into information products.
我對資訊產品沒興趣
But many live in places like Thailand and Dubai,
但有很多人住在泰國和杜拜
and I think just meeting and talking to them would be insightful.
如果能和他們見面談談 應該能學到一些事
Will those people meet with you?
那些人願意見你嗎？
I don't think there's anyone else with such initiative to come and meet them.
他們應該沒碰過我這種超有行動力
You don't need to do that.
不用做到那種程度吧
Just by changing your goal from the judicial exam, you've changed a lot.
光是改變考過司法考試這個目標 就算是很大的轉變了
It's not about that.
不是那樣啦
I want to change my perspective on life.
我想改變的是人生觀
What do you think?
你覺得呢？
Just to be sure. You're not asking me for money, are you?
我確認一下，你打來不是為了錢吧？
Of course not. I'll go by myself.
那當然，我會自己想辦法去
Please exchange this for Thai currency.
請幫我換成泰國的貨幣
Oh, here.
哦，是這裡啊
To Narita Airport, please.
請載我去成田機場
I overslept on the day of my flight.
搭機那天不知為何竟睡過了頭
I actually didn't want to pay for a taxi.
我根本不想付這筆計程車費
Money's tight for me this month,
其實我這個月手頭很緊
so I'm grateful for this drive to Narita Airport.
所以這趟載你去成田機場 真的幫了我大忙
No problem.
不用謝
I considered that paying this person may have been a good thing.
我開始覺得也許付錢給她是件好事
In the end, the only thing I'm good for is borrowing money and spending it on others.
結果借了錢，用在別人身上 是我唯一派得上用場的地方
Watanabe was disheartened but searched for tickets he could buy on the spot.
渡邊並沒有消沉太久 他開始尋找當下能買得到的機票
I don't mind the destination,
哪裡都可以
but are there any tickets still available for a flight to Asia?
現在還有任何飛往亞洲的 航班機票嗎？
Watanabe came to meet famous influencers living in Dubai.
渡邊來見住在杜拜的知名網紅們
However, he did not know any of them personally,
話雖這麼說，他不認識任何一人
nor did he have their contact information.
當然也不知道他們的聯絡方式
What drove Watanabe was a mentality similar to that of gambling.
驅使渡邊採取行動的 是類似賭博的心態
Naturally, they didn't conveniently appear in the places he had seen on social media,
但他們當然不會恰巧出現在 他曾在社群媒體上看過的地方
and time passed by.
時間就這樣過去了
No negotiation here.
我們不能在這裡談價碼
Hotel first.
要先去飯店
You speak Japanese?
你會說日文？
Half Asian.
我是半個亞洲人
Let's go. Which way?
走吧，要去哪？
But I need to know the price first.
但我需要先知道價錢
1,000 dirhams.
一千迪拉姆
Okay.
好
I do have money, you know?
我是真的有錢
Just give me a minute.
等我一下
Right…
對了
This is bad.
糟透了
Seriously bad.
真的不妙
I was actually planning on going to Thailand today.
我今天本來要去泰國
So I exchanged yen for baht and not dirhams.
我把日幣換成了泰銖 沒有換成迪拉姆
I thought…
我想說啊
it would be fine since I have a credit card.
還有信用卡，應該沒關係
That's why I don't have dirhams on me.
所以沒有迪拉姆
I have money and I am definitely going to pay you.
我有錢，我一定會付你錢的
The banks are closed now, right?
不過銀行現在也關門了對吧？
Ugh…
呃…
I could pay you in baht but…
我是能付你泰銖啦…
No, that's not…
那樣我會有點困擾耶
I know.
說得也是
Um…
嗯…
you know what?
可是這些錢…
Let me calculate how much this would be in dirhams.
我來算算看這些換成迪拉姆值多少錢
So…
所以呢
Let's see…
我來查一下
Oh, wrong number.
啊，打錯了
Um…
我看看
One second.
快好了
-No need to rush. -Hm.
-不要急 -嗯
Okay, yeah…
算好了，那個…
I have 1,000 dirhams. No problem at all.
我這裡絕對有一千迪拉姆，我敢保證
Here.
給你吧
How about I pay you in baht?
我用泰銖付給你，好嗎？
Those are genuine baht bills.
這是真的泰銖
I can give you more than 1,000 dirhams' worth if you want.
如果你願意，我會付給你 超過一千迪拉姆的泰銖
I can't make out if they're really genuine,
我分不出來是不是真的啊
so I'll stay here until you can exchange it.
到明天換完錢為止，我會待在這裡
In fact, this incident brought Watanabe and Rina closer.
事實上，這晚成為渡邊和莉娜 對彼此敞開心胸的契機
Rina became the first friend Watanabe made as an adult.
對渡邊來說莉娜是他長大後 第一次交到的朋友
But that's a story for another time.
但這又是另一段故事了
Have you ever been to Japan?
你有去過日本嗎？
It's the opposite.
應該說正好相反
What do you mean?
是什麼意思？
Actually,
其實啊
I lied about being mixed.
我不是混血兒，我騙了你
Well, it happens.
是喔，也是會有這種事啦
I came here to work because I can make more money.
我是來這裡打工賺錢 這裡能賺的比日本還多
By standing?
靠站壁嗎？
There used to be a middleman who would refer clients to me.
其實本來有一個仲介大哥 他會介紹客人給我
I made good money the first time I came, and this is my second time.
我第一次來的時候賺了很多錢 這是我第二次來
But apparently, it wasn't allowed
但介紹客人的行為好像是違法的
and the middleman got caught.
那位大哥被抓了
I didn't want to go home without earning anything.
我不想什麼都沒賺到就回家
I didn't want to end up losing money on the flight.
也不想虧掉機票錢
Did you come alone?
大哥是一個人來的嗎？
Yeah, well…
這個嘛，是啊
I'm not here on vacation.
我不是來旅行的
-Oh? -Yeah.
-是喔 -對
I'm here to learn something, even though I haven't done anything productive yet.
應該說我是來學習的 但什麼目標都還沒有達成就是了
What do you want to learn?
你是來學什麼的？
Well…
這個嘛…
About life.
像是人生啊
Values.
價值觀之類的
Standards. I want to figure out stuff like that.
還有準則，我想試著建立起這些東西
I see.
是喔
What do you do for a living?
你的工作是什麼？
Nothing.
我沒有工作
I actually wanted to get into law to help people, you know?
我本來想用法律去幫助別人
Uh-huh.
嗯
But I failed the judicial exam every time.
但就是考不過司法考試
So I gave up recently.
所以最近放棄了
I wanted to get a job but at my age…
就算想找工作，但我都這把年紀了…
So I worked some part-time jobs.
我也去打了一些工
I wanted to live an age-appropriate life
我渴望過上符合年紀的生活
and thought I'd try out different things.
所以決定多方嘗試
Right.
這樣啊
Did you learn anything today?
你今天有學到什麼嗎？
No, today I didn't learn anything.
沒有，今天完全沒收穫
The people I saw on social media aren't anywhere to be found.
完全找不到那些 在社群媒體上看到的傢伙們
Have you met any of them in Dubai?
你有在杜拜遇過他們嗎？
No, I haven't.
沒遇過
I see.
是喔
How about getting a regular job?
普通地找份工作比較好吧？
It's not possible.
不可能啦
At my age, I can't start over anymore.
因為我已經過了能重新開始的年齡
But--
但是啊…
I'm even belittled at my part-time jobs.
我在打工的地方也被瞧不起
Be it getting qualifications or going out for fun, everything costs money.
不管是考證照或是出去玩 做什麼都要錢
-But-- -I can't get a regular life anymore.
-可是… -我已經沒辦法過普通的生活了
But--
可是…
No "buts."
別再說“可是”了
It's just impossible for me.
我已經不行了
What others are allowed to do, I'm not anymore.
別人能夠做的事，我已經辦不到了
It's enough for me if I can watch one movie a month.
每個月能看上一部電影就好
It's enough if I can go out for drinks with friends twice a month.
每個月能跟朋友去喝兩次酒就好
With the jobs I can still get, I can't afford to treat my sister to a meal
我今後能做的工作無法請姊姊吃飯
or to take my mother on a trip for Mother's Day.
也沒辦法在母親節帶我媽媽去旅行
I can't start over anymore.
我已經不能重新開始了
Had I known life doesn't allow do-overs,
早知道人生無法重來
I wouldn't have bothered taking the exams.
我一開始就不會去考什麼試
I hope you find a job soon.
希望你能找到工作
It's double my price.
這是兩倍的錢，我可以收下嗎？
I don't need it anymore, so take it.
我用不到了，就給你吧
Okay,
好
when I'm back in Japan, I'll treat you to a meal. Just once, though.
回日本之後我請你吃飯，就請一次
Go enjoy some good food in Dubai.
你就在杜拜吃點好吃的吧
Where in Tokyo do you live?
你住在東京的哪裡？
In Iogi.
井荻
I'm planning to tell my sister that I'm going to enter the orifices.
接下來我準備跟我姊說 要進去洞裡的事
Your story isn't embarrassing at all.
你的故事一點都不丟臉啊
Of course it is.
很丟臉啊
Not at all.
完全不會
Did you go have a meal with that person in Japan?
你跟那個人後來有在日本吃飯嗎？
Ah, yes.
有啊
We met a few times.
我們見過好幾次
I hadn't expected to become friends with her.
沒想到我們會變成朋友
It's easier to make friends when you're abroad, right? I totally get you.
到國外就很容易跟別人成為朋友 我超級懂那種感覺
I don't know her real name, though.
但我不知道她的本名
-Could you pass me the wine? -Sure.
-可以幫我倒葡萄酒嗎？ -好
-Here you go. -Thank you.
-來 -謝謝
I've never stolen anything.
我從來沒有偷過東西
Don't do it.
千萬別做啊
Although the ice cream was delicious.
雖然冰很好吃
Watanabe hadn't met his sister since he informed her about going to Dubai.
渡邊自從告訴姊姊要去杜拜之後 就再也沒和她見過面
Oh, I see.
哦，對
I'm actually on my way right now.
待會就要進去了
What?
什麼？
No.
不
Yeah, but…
但是啊…
Well…
是可以啦
It's not urgent,
也不急
so I could turn around and come meet you.
是可以回頭和你見面
But…
不過呢…
Well, yeah,
是啦
I don't have to enter the orifices today.
也不是今天就一定要進去洞裡
On that day, Watanabe went to see his sister and his mother.
這一天渡邊去見了他媽媽和姊姊
Watanabe lamented that his life was one where he couldn't obtain what he desired.
渡邊抱怨他的人生 總是得不到想要的東西
His sister suggested that he join the company she was working for,
姊姊便勸他去自己就職的公司工作
making it his first full-time job.
這是他的第一份全職工作
Subtitle translation by: Mariko Yasuoka-Sator
字幕翻譯：黃可涵
I'm SHINGO.
我是SHINGO
I managed to produce hotels and guesthouses.
我從事飯店和民宿策劃的生意很順利
Your hotel in Oita was quite the buzz.
大分那間飯店爆紅了
It hit my highest revenue ever.
創下至今最高的紀錄
Your videos have never hit it big.
你從來沒有成功過，甚至沒被我認同
What he did to me won't disappear.
我遭受的對待不會就此消失
Seven Orifices.
《驚天七洞》